Ujjwal Poudel

40 Bickerton Crescent, North York, Ontario | 437-557-1889

ujjwal.poudel.2003@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/poudel-ujjwal

A collaborative and technically competent student of Software Engineering Technology, specializing in Software development. Developed foundational knowledge of Web Application Development, object-oriented programming, Database Management System and Agile Software Development practices. Profound knowledge of front-end technology and software engineering with C#(.Net) and Java. Possess significant interpersonal and communication skills as a Tutor at Centennial College.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• React.js	 MERN Stack 	• C# (.Net)
• Figma	• DBMS (Oracle)	Python
 Git/GitHub 	• Jira	 Unix/Linux OS
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript 	 Node.js 	 MongoDB
 Responsive Web Design 	Java	 Agile/Scrum

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Technology - Artificial Intelligence Advanced Diploma

Jan. 2023 - Present

Coursework: Web Application Development | Software Systems Design | C# Programming | Java Programming | Web Interface Design | Software Engineering Requirements | Client-Side Development GitHub: https://github.com/UjjwalPoudel2003/Semester 2

PROJECTS

Word Cloud Generator

Centennial College, Toronto, ON

Developed a web application that allows users to generate word clouds from text input or URL. This application can be used to find the key words or repeated word from text description. Cross-origin resource sharing (CORS) blocks to fetch text from different URLs.

Project GitHub link: https://github.com/UjjwalPoudel2003/word-cloud-generator
Project Design link: https://shorturl.at/dkUW7

- Asynchronous operations, data fetching, text processing, and word cloud generation algorithms, along with custom styling using HTML and CSS
- Utilized web technologies like working with external APIs and employing asynchronous JavaScript operations, to optimize application functionality and performance.
- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for front-end development and a responsive, user-oriented interface
- Developed a word cloud generator with precise word frequency analysis.

Personal Portfolio (Ongoing)

Using React.js library to create a Personal Portfolio. Using MERN stack to relate with my course work. The portfolio will showcase web development projects, skills and achievements.

Project GitHub link: https://github.com/UjjwalPoudel2003/Personal-Website
Project Design link: https://shorturl.at/fhEHM

- Created different Navbar and page body component using React components.
- Styled the portfolio using CSS styling for an appealing design.
- Planned to use React routing to ensure smooth navigation within the portfolio.

Payroll Calculator (Ongoing)

Created a GUI based application created with C# in .Net framework. User provides a time stamp in input and outputs the number of hours, minutes and seconds spent on the timeframe.

Ujjwal Poudel

40 Bickerton Crescent, North York, Ontario | 437-557-1889 ujjwal.poudel.2003@gmail.com

Projects continued...

Project GitHub link: https://github.com/UjjwalPoudel2003/PayrollCalculator

- Utilized OOP concepts, including encapsulation (private variables), constructors, and methods.
- Employed the Date Time library for working with date and time-related calculations, including recording the current date and handling time-in and time-out inputs.
- Project includes GUI interface using Windows Forms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Academic Tutor | Centennial College, Toronto, ON

May 2023 - Present

- Provide one-on-one and group tutoring through Centennial Libraries tutoring program, to students in subjects related to Math, Web Development, Python, Database (SQL), and C# courses.
- Use various teaching and learning strategies, ensuring adherence to college tutoring polices and standards; Completed CRLA Certification for Tutoring to ensure quality service delivery to students.
- Exceeded the set tutoring sessions targets, contributed to enhance students' academic performance, heightened students' confidence and resulted notable grade improvements.
- Achieved an impressive 99% increase in student satisfaction because of quality tutoring.

Crew Member/Trainer | McDonald's, Toronto, ON

Feb. 2023 - Present

- Provide quality customer service and process transactions in a fast-paced & high-volume environment, consistently exceeding weekly sales goals by 10%.
- Trained and supervised new crew members, providing supportive guidance, feedback and ensuring they met company standards for quality, cleanliness, and service.
- Demonstrated strong leadership and communication skills by leading shift and coordinating activities.
- Developed time management skills, maintaining a busy work schedule while balancing academics.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- CRLA Certification | Tutor Evaluation Program | 2023
- React.js Essential Training | LinkedIn Learning | 2023
- Figma Essentials Training | LinkedIn Learning | 2023
- Git Essentials Training | LinkedIn Learning | 2023
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript Training | LinkedIn Learning | 2023